Fathin Dosunmu

FullStack Software Engineer

Address Tallinn, Harjumaa (Tallinn), 12611

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/fathindos/

Phone +37253653094

WWW https://fato07.github.io/home

E-mail Fathindos.fd@gmail.com

Web Developer with 3 years of experience in frontend and backend development. Seasoned expert in technologies such as react js, firebase, node js, Typescript and Web Security. Experience designing and developing websites from concept to roll out and Passionate about cyber security. Even though I love to get my work done in the best way, I have a great sense of humor.

Skills

Firebase, Google Cloud API	Excellent
React js, Javascript, Typescript, Node JS	Excellent
HTML5, CSS3, SASS, styled components	Excellent
REST	Excellent
GraphQL	Average
StateManagement: Recoil, Redux	Excellent
CMS: Drupal, Contentful	Good
Git, Confluence	Excellent
Clean Code, Clean Architecture, SOLID principles	Excellent
CI/CD, Jenkins, Docker	Excellent
Can adapt to new tools and frameworks	Excellent
Semantic UI, Material UI	Excellent
Express	Excellent
Node Js	Excellent
Linux	Excellent

Work History

2022-10 - Current

Front End Software Developer

Monese, Tallinn

2021-09 - 2022-09

Developer

Exove, Tallinn, Harjumaa (Tallinn)

- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Developed programs from ground up using measured, market-focused approach to eliminate waste and streamline implementation cycle.
- · Creating new features for clients with React js, node js, redux, firebase and more
- Checked client code for bugs and weaknesses using approved troubleshooting methods.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers for clients.
- Tested web-based product functionality and delivered iterations to clients.
- Researched emerging web technologies and trends for possible incorporation into sites.

2021-07 - 2021-08

Frontend Developer Intern

Kuehne+nagel, Tallinn, Estonia

Key Responsibilities

- Main focus on Redux and its implementations in large scale applications.
- Managed full-cycle design tasks, handling all phases from conception to completion while maintaining guidelines throughout.
- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.

2021-02 - 2021-05

Web Developer

Fundamental Secrets, Florida, United Sates

Key Responsibilities

- Responsible for developing website product used by approximately 600 + users
- Planned website development, converting ideas into features with HTML, JavaScript, React-js and Firebase
- Implemented payment gateways with Paypal and Stripe.
- Oversaw front-end with mainly React-js and back-end development with mainly firebase.
- Multitasked across multiple functions and ideas to generate project results and meet deadlines.
- · Engaged with marketing officer to plan, optimize and repair issues as work environment was changing rapidly.
- Product built and was responsible for: https://fundamentalsecrets.web.app/

2020-06 - 2020-08

Test Developer Intern

Ericsson, Tallinn, Estonia

Key Responsibilities

- Prepared Software For Testing 5G units before Production.
- Optimized existing code for software Tool within Ericsson's Tech Stack. (C#, SQL and MDX).
- Prepared and Implemented Test criteria and Test Plan in Test Programs for High-Band Products.

Education

2020-09 - Current

Master of Science: Cyber Security

• Https://www.taltech.ee/en/cyber-msc

2017-09 - 2020-06

Bachelor of Science: Integrated Engineering

Taltech - Tallinn, Estonia

• Https://www.taltech.ee/en/integrated-engineering.

Hobby Projects

- Personal Blogpost, where i write about cyber security, hacking and the interesting machine i have hacked on tryhackme: https://medium.com/@fathindos.fd
- Personal Website to showcase my skillset: https://fato07.github.io/home/
- Built a clone of whatsApp Chat. A User can signIn, Post a chat in a chat room and chat with other users:
 https://whatsapp-clone-bd456.web.app/ (React js and Firebase for development)